Curriculum Vitae

Vit Gabrhel

2020-10-11

Introduction

Hi, I am a data analyst with experience in the field of travel behaviour analysis, travel demand modelling, customer experience, customer satisfaction, and product analysis. I am an independent user of statistical packages (R, Python, Google Sheets, MS Excel) and database quering languages/dialects (PostgreSQL, MySQL, Snowflake, Standard SQL in BigQuery) with experience in areas ranging from the data collection through its wrangling, description, visualisation to the advanced linear models (regression models, PCA, SEM). Lately, I have gained experience with data science techniques (like segmentation or recommendation engine) and data engineering areas (ETL, data models, data architecture).

Work Experience

Data Analyst

Meiro, Brno, Czech Republic 08/2020-Present

- Covered domains: Data Engineering, Data Analysis, Data Science.
- ETL pipelines management, Design of data models.
- Integrating PostgreSQL and MySQL with R and Python, data wrangling, description, and visualization to advanced statistical techniques and data science techniques (e.g. recommendation engine
 and customer segmentation) in Python using VS Code. Fundamentals of Spark.
- Linux desktop (Ubuntu), Bash, Git. Fundamentals of **Docker** and **CD/CI**.

Data Analyst

Kiwi.com, Brno, Czech Republic 04/2019-07/2020

- Covered domains: Product, Customer Experience, Customer Support.
- Reports. Integrating PostgreSQL, Snowflake, and BigQuery with R and Python, data wrangling, description, and visualization to advanced statistical techniques (regression models, structural equation modelling) in R. Reporting in Markdown (R notebooks, Jupyter Notebooks, oral presentations).
- Dashboards. I'm proficient in working with tools like Looker, GoodData, Google Data Studio, or Retool (Plotly).
- Data engineering. Sense of data models and ETL self-service (Keboola, dbt).
- Linux desktop (Ubuntu), Bash, Git.
- Jira, Scrum.

Lecturer

Masaryk University, Brno, Czech Republic 09/2015-Present

- Demonstrations of analyses and their interpretations, providing oral and written feedback in the following courses:
 - Statistical Data Analysis I.

- * Correlation, contingency tables, t-test, an introduction to non-parametric tests (e.g. chi-square).
- Statistical Data Analysis II.
 - * Multiple linear regression, ANOVA, logistic regression, factor analysis, mixed effect models.
- An Introduction to R
 - * An introduction to the **R language**, data cleaning, wrangling, description and visualization, multivariate analyses in the R language.

Researcher

Transport Research Centre, Brno, Czech Republic 06/2015-03/2019

- Travel behaviour analyses, coordination of research activities, communication with the lay public as well as the community of experts.
- Investigator in the project Česko v pohybu. Development of the research tool, development and implementation of the probabilistic sampling procedure and algorithms for automated control of the data quality.
- Methodological and analytical supervision of the research project for the Czech Ministry of Transport related to the Public opinion on autonomous vehicles.
- Project management of small project teams, e.g. program section for the conference Dopravní chování v datech.

Education

Psychology (Ph.D.)

Masaryk University, Brno, Czech Republic 09/2015-Present

- Specialisation in advanced analytical methods structural equation modelling, multinomial regression.
- Member of the Disciplinary Committee Faculty of Social Studies.

Psychology (Master degree)

Masaryk University, Brno, Czech Republic 2013–2015

- Specialisation in **frequentist statistics**, introduction to Bayesian statistics.
- Scholarship for excellent performance in research activities given by the Faculty of Social Studies during the academic year 2013/2014.
- Thesis: Student Styles Questionnaire in the Czech context: A pilot study
- Graduated with honours.

Psychology and Sociology (Bachelor degree)

Masaryk University, Brno, Czech Republic 2010–2013

Specialisation in quantitative methodology and statistical data analysis in IBM SPSS with focus on linear models. Scholarship for best students of Faculty of Social Studies during the academic years 2010/2011 and 2011/2012. Thesis: The relationship between spirituality and autonomy in late adolescence and emerging adulthood. Graduated with honours.

Internships

Danmarks Tekniske Universitet, Management Engineering, Lyngby, Denmark. 08-09/2017

Corpus Christi College, University of Cambridge, Cambridge, UK. 07-09/2015

Selected publications

- Gabrhel, V., Ježek, S. (2017). Factor validity and internal consistency of the Expressions of Spirituality Inventory Revised (ESI-R): The Czech context. International Journal of Transpersonal Studies, 36 (1), 101-109. doi:10.24972/ijts.2017.36.1.101.
- Gabrhel, V. (2019). Feeling like cycling? Psychological factors related to cycling as a mode choice. Transactions on Transport Sciences, 10 (1). doi:10.1007/978-3-319-60441-1_80
- Gabrhel, V., Ježek, S., Havlíčková, D. (2019). Public opinion on connected and automated vehicles: the Czech context. Transactions on Transport Sciences, 10 (2). doi:10.5507/tots.2019.011
- Havlíčková, D., Gabrhel, V., Adamovská, E., Zámečník, P. (2019). The role of gender and age in autonomous mobility: general attitude, awareness and media preference in the context of Czech Republic. Transactions on Transport Sciences, 10 (2). doi:10.5507/tots.2019.013
- Jakopec, A., Gabrhel, V., Keane, L., Kovač, N., Reigbert, K., Andersen, T. L. (2015). Work Engagement and Performance: Does the (Mis)Alignment of Justice Sources Matter? Journal of European Psychology Students, 6 (2), 75–78. doi:10.5334/jeps.cs.
- Kurečková, V., Gabrhel, V., Zámečník, P., et al. (2017) First aid as an important traffic safety factor – evaluation of the experience–based training. European Transport Research Review, 9 (5). doi:10.1007/s12544-016-0218-4/
- Šimeček, M., Gabrhel, V., Tögel, M., & Lazor, M. (2018). Travel behaviour of seniors in Eastern Europe: a comparative study of Brno and Bratislava. European Transport Research Review, 10 (16), 1-8. doi:10.1007/s12544-018-0286-8
- Švarcová, J., Gabrhel, V. (2014). Educational Mobility and Educational Aspirations of High School Students in the Czech Republic. The International Journal of Interdisciplinary Educational Studies, 8 (2), 1-12.
- Švarcová, J., Harantová, L., & Gabrhel, V. (2013). Statistical analysis of student's interest in creative professions in the Czech Republic. International Journal of Mathematical Models and Methods in Applied Sciences, 7 (2), 444-451.

Selected talks

- Gabrhel, V., Šenk, P., Lazor, M., & Ondráčková, J. (2016). Travel Behavior in Central and Eastern Europe: a Bratislava Case Study. Paper presented at the World Conference on Transport Research – WCTR 2016 Shanghai in Shanghai, People's Republic of China.
- Gabrhel, V. (2018). Public opinion on automated vehicles: the Czech context. Paper presented at the conference Silniční konference 2018 in Ostrava, Czech Republic.
- Gabrhel, V., Zámečník, P. (2018). Concerns related to the interaction between autonomous vehicles
 and other transport systém users. Paper presented at the conference Road Safety on Five Continents in
 Jeju, Republic of Korea.
- Šimeček, M., Gabrhel, V., Togel, M., & Lazor, M. (2016). Travel behaviour of seniors in Central Europe: a comparative study of Brno and Bratislava. Paper presented at the conference NECTAR Joint Cluster 2 and Cluster 3 International Workshop "The role of planning towards sustainable urban mobility" in Brno, Czech Republic.